Rachel Kocheran

Data Analyst

rkkocheran@gmail.com

1 615-917-2582



Nashville, TN



github.com/rkkocheran



linkedin.com/in/rachelkocheran

Skills

- SQL
- Pvthon
- Tableau
- **PowerBI**
- Excel
- PowerPivot / PivotTables
- Git/GitHub
- FTI Process
- ER Models

Education

Data Analytics Certification

Nashville Software School

Bioinformatics. B.S.

University of California, Santa Cruz

Work Experience

Wild Birds Unlimited

Sales Associate Jun 2020 - Sep 2022

- Operated/troubleshooted POS systems
- Assessed customer needs
- Maintained sales floor inventory

Nashville Pet Products

Key Holder Jul 2019 - Jun 2020

- Performed opening/closing tasks
- Processed customer orders

Nature's Best Nursery

Retail Associate Oct 2018 - Jun 2019

Self-Employed

Childcare Provider Oct 2010 - Oct 2018

Profile

From daily challenges to long-term projects, SQL scripting to database diving, the more complex the problem, the more I'm driven to succeed. Capitalizing on my experience in childcare and retail, I now invest in Data Analytics. With a natural penchant for creative solutions, I look forward to contributing to the dynamic and swiftly growing field of data exploration and visualization.

Data Analytics Experience

Nashville Software School

Sep 2022 - Jan 2023

Data Analyst Apprentice

Full-time bootcamp focused on data analytics fundamentals and problem solving. Incorporated real-world datasets and presentations of analyses to stakeholders.

- Analyzed data using Microsoft Excel, pivot tables and lookups, and connected to external data sources using the PowerPivot add-on
- Built and deployed dashboards using Tableau and PowerBI
- Performed exploratory data analysis using Python's pandas library
- Created data visualizations using matplotlib and seaborn
- Gathered data through APIs and webscraping
- Performed geospatial analysis using geopandas and folium
- Retrieved and analyzed data using PostgreSQL and sqlalchemy
- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Project management/tracking with GitHub project boards and issue tracking

Projects

What's In Your Air? A Comparative Study of Nashville's Air Quality

Analyzed air quality trends across the US with a focus on Nashville to determine differences in pollen varieties and levels of airborne particulate matter.

Skills employed: Tableau, Python, Jupyter Notebooks, Anaconda, Microsoft Excel

Project FeederWatch Observations for Tennessee

Analyzed citizen-scientist observation data from Project FeederWatch to determine songbird migration and participant submission patterns in Tennessee.

Skills employed: Tableau, SQL, PostgreSQL, pgAdmin

App Trader Analysis

Analyzed mobile app data to develop recommendations as to price range, genre, content rating, etc. for apps to be targeted by App Trader.

Skills employed: SQL (CTEs, Joins, Window Functions), PostgreSQL, pgAdmin, Microsoft Excel (LOOKUPs)

Statistical Analysis of the Lahman Baseball Database

Performed exploratory analyses on the Lahman Baseball database to determine player, team and managerial statistics.

Skills employed: SQL (CTEs, Subqueries, Joins, Window Functions), PostgreSQL, pgAdmin, ERDs

Analysis of TN Medicare Part D Prescriber and Prescription Data

Explored medical provider, prescription, medication and county-level data using PowerBI and SQL to calculate various prescription statistics.

Skills employed: PowerBI, SQL, PostgreSQL, pgAdmin, ERDs